mspmag.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy | The Best of the Twin Cities | Mpls.St.Paul Magazine - Mpls.St.Paul Magazine

**Welcome to mspmag.com**

Thank you for visiting mspmag.com, a _Mpls.St.Paul Magazine_ website. Your privacy is important to us. To better protect your privacy, we provide this notice explaining our online information practices. We want you to be aware of any user information we collect, how we use it, and under what circumstances, if any, we disclose it. To that end, we collect and use information throughout mspmag.com only as disclosed in this privacy policy. This statement applies solely to information collected on this website, mspmag.com.

mspmag.com is created, edited, and maintained by MSP Communications, publisher of _Mpls.St.Paul Magazine_ , 220 S. 6th St., Ste. 500, Minneapolis, MN 55402.

MSP COMMUNICATIONS PRIVACY POLICY

Effective date August 31, 2018

This Privacy Policy describes how your personal information is collected, used, shared and protected when you visit, use or make a purchase from mspmag.com or tcbmag.com, owned by Key Enterprises LLC dba MSP Communications (the “Site”, “We”).

This policy applies where we are acting as a data controller with respect to the personal data of our website visitors, email subscribers, magazine subscribers and event registrants; in other words, where we determine the purposes and means of the processing of that personal data.

If you do not agree to the Terms of Use and this Privacy Policy, you must discontinue using the Site and all services and features therein. By using the Site you acknowledge you have read and understand this Privacy Policy.

PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT

When you visit the Site, we automatically collect certain information about your device, including information about your web browser, IP address, time zone, and some of the cookies that are installed on your device. Additionally, as you browse the Site, we collect information about the individual web pages or content that you view, what websites or search terms referred you to the Site, and information about how you interact with the Site. We refer to this automatically-collected information as “Device Information.”

When we talk about “Personal Information” in this Privacy Policy, we are talking both about Device Information and Order Information.

DEVICE INFORMATION

In order to serve you in the best capacity possible, we use the Device Information that we collect to help us screen for potential risk and fraud (in particular, your IP address), and more generally to improve and optimize our Site (for example, by generating analytics about how our customers browse and interact with the Site, and to assess the success of our marketing and advertising campaigns).

We collect Device Information using the following technologies:

COOKIES

Cookies are small data files that are placed on your device and often include an anonymous unique identifier. The placement of cookies allows the Site to recognize your device and aids in the collection of browsing information to help us make the ads and content we display more relevant to you. In some cases, you won’t be able to fully take advantage of various features available without accepting cookies to be placed on your device.

Cookies do not typically contain any information that personally identifies a user, but personal information that we store about you may be linked to the information stored in and obtained from cookies.

Our advertising and marketing partners may also use their own cookies; we are not responsible for their activities and policies on the issue.

For more information about cookies, and how to disable cookies, visit [http://www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/).

Most browsers allow you to refuse to accept cookies and to delete cookies. The methods for doing so vary from browser to browser, and from version to version. You can however obtain up-to-date information about blocking and deleting cookies via these links:

ADDITIONAL TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES

Log files track actions occurring on the Site, and collect data including your IP address, browser type, Internet service provider, referring/exit pages, and date/time stamps.

Web beacons, tags, and pixels are electronic files used to record information about how you browse the Site.

SOCIAL NETWORKING

You can access various social networks and sharing tools from our Site that are operated by third parties, that allow you to post links to content and features that you believe will be of interest to others on your social network pages. When you visit a page that includes one of these sharing tools, the third-party company that operates the tool may be collecting device information through its own tracking technologies and subject to its own separate privacy policy.

ORDER INFORMATION

When you sign up for a subscription or make a purchase or attempt to make a purchase through the Site, we collect certain personal information from you, including your name, billing address, shipping address, payment information (including credit card numbers), email address, and phone number. We refer to this information as “Order Information.”

On occasion we will ask for demographic information as it relates to your working persona and the company you work for such as title, gender, age, industry, number of employees and sales revenue. This information will be required if subscribing to business magazines published by MSP Communications.

HOW WE USE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We use the Order Information that we collect generally for shipping and billing purposes and to fulfill your orders.

Additionally, we may use Device and Order Information for the following purposes:

  * To improve the content of the magazines, websites and newsletters
  * To notify subscribers about requalification and renewal
  * For marketing sponsored products and services
  * For our circulation audit to verify demographic statistics, subscription transactions and web activity
  * For research surveys
  * Used by editors for consultation with readers

Postal addresses (only those in the United States) may be rented to select outside firms for promotional purposes. Users are required to target their offers carefully and are reviewed and monitored by the MSP Communications team.

Telephone numbers of subscribers (only in the United States) are used to collect renewal and requalification information. We operate in compliance of the law regulated by the Federal Trade Commission. Go here for more information <https://www.ftc.gov/>. You may choose to not receive phone calls from us by either registering your phone number on the Do Not Call list at <https://www.donotcall.gov/> or by contacting us directly at which time we will update your preference to not be called. Telephone numbers are not rented to outside firms.

Your e-mail address will be used to send you the content you have requested, to notify you of subscription expiration and renewal instructions and to send you offers we think may interest you. They also may be used for surveys conducted by our own research team. E-mail addresses are not rented to outside firms. When you provide your email address to us, you agree to receive email from us. We allow you to "opt-out" of receiving email at the time you subscribe and within each email you receive from us.

We use the Device Information that we collect to improve and optimize our Site by generating analytics about how our customers browse and interact with the Site. This allows us to measure usage patterns to improve the quality of our content and your experience and to assess the success of our marketing and advertising campaigns. Google Analytics is our primary tool for analyzing the Device Information collected. You can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information here: <https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/>.

You can also opt-out of Google Analytics here: <https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>.

Other sources of usage data may be be collected in Watson Campaign Automation, Universal Behavior Exchange, DoubleClick, AddThis, Simplifi, Facebook, Instagram and Twitter.

BEHAVIORAL ADVERTISING

As noted above, we use your Device Information to provide you with targeted advertisements or marketing communications we believe may be of interest to you. For more information about how targeted advertising works, you can visit the Network Advertising Initiative’s (“NAI”) educational page at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/understanding-online-advertising/how-does-it-work>.

You can opt out of targeted advertising by:

  * FACEBOOK - <https://www.facebook.com/settings/?tab=ads>
  * GOOGLE - <https://www.google.com/settings/ads/anonymous>
  * BING - <https://advertise.bingads.microsoft.com/en-us/resources/policies/personalized-ads>

Additionally, you can opt out of some of these services by visiting the Digital Advertising Alliance’s opt-out portal at: <http://optout.aboutads.info/>.

SHARING YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION

We will disclose your name, address, email address, transaction information and demographic information, email communication and activity data to our fulfillment partners in order to effect the transaction and send you the product you have ordered, and we will disclose your credit card details to the relevant bank or credit card processor in order to complete the transaction. Our print magazine fulfillment partner is CDS Global and our email newsletter platform is Watson Campaign Automation. For more information about either, see links below.

Finally, we may also share your Personal Information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful request for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

DO NOT TRACK

Please note that we do not alter our Site’s data collection and use practices when we see a Do Not Track signal from your browser.

YOUR RIGHTS

If you are a European resident, you have the right to access personal information we hold about you and to ask that your personal information be corrected, updated, or deleted. If you would like to exercise this right, please email our Privacy Policy Coordinator at [technicalsupport@mspcommunications.com](mailto:technicalsupport@mspcommunications.com). Please include your full name, email used to send our newsletters to you, company and country. If necessary to confirm your identity for erasure, we will respond with a request for more detail. We will respond to your request within 30 days.

Additionally, if you are a European resident, note that we are processing and storing your information in order to fulfill the purposes for which it was collected (for example if you make an order through the Site), or otherwise to pursue our legitimate business interests listed above. Your personal information may be transferred to, stored and accessed by us and our affiliated data processors where they operate in the United States. By using the Site, you consent to this transfer, processing, storage and access of your personal information outside of the jurisdiction in which you reside. We will transfer your personal information subject to suitable safeguards.

DATA RETENTION

When you place an order through the Site, we will maintain your Order Information for our records unless and until you ask us to delete this information.

MINORS

This Site is not intended for minors under the age of eighteen. In order to protect them, minors are not permitted to register for the site; provide any personal information; purchase subscriptions; or use our public discussion areas, forums, and chats without the permission of their parents or legal guardians.

You should encourage your children not to use our site, because if they disclose information about themselves in our public discussion areas or on our blogs, they may get unsolicited messages from other parties. If you're worried about your children's activities on our site, we encourage you to email our Privacy Policy Coordinator at [technicalsupport@mspcommunications.com](mailto:technicalsupport@mspcommunications.com).

CHANGES

We may update this privacy policy from time to time in order to reflect, for example, changes to our practices or for other operational, legal or regulatory reasons. If we append to or make changes concerning our privacy practices online, however, we will post those changes within this privacy policy. You agree that any subsequent use by you of this Site following changes to this policy will constitute your acceptance of all such changes.

If any conflicts or disputes arise with our privacy policy, we commit to resolve it within forty-eight hours. Should a situation such as this occur, users may contact us at the e-mail address, mailing address, or telephone number listed below.

CONTACT US

If you have any general questions about this privacy policy, please also feel free to contact us at: [technicalsupport@mspcommunications.com](mailto:technicalsupport@mspcommunications.com).

MSP Communications

220 S. 6th St., Ste. 500

Minneapolis, MN 55402

612-339-7571

Fax: 612-339-5806

Effective August 31, 2018
